## IAN ISKANDAR

ianiskand11@gmail.com | +6288211005452 | Karawang, Indonesia | linkedin.com/in/ian-iskandar-b953bb193

#### **SUMMARY**

Bachelor's degree in computer engineering with an understanding of various aspects of information technology. I have skills in using Microsoft Office and experience in managing Digital Marketing platforms, such as online Advertising Campaigns and Data analysis. In addition, I have expertise in managing websites using WordPress and understand the importance of Social Media strategies in building a strong online presence. I am ready to bring this knowledge and skills into a role that requires a deep understanding of technology and Digital Marketing.

#### **EDUCATION**

Computer Engineering, STMIK Rosma

2019 - 2023

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## **WordPress Dev at Perum Perumnas**

August 8th 2022 – November 8th, 2022

- Find and ensure several updated plugins that have a significant effect on visitor satisfaction for at least 5% of each visitor.
- Implement SEO on the website to appear at the level of related keywords in the Google search engine at least on the first 1 or 2 search page.
- Analyzed user requirements and software specifications to identify key trouble spots and areas for improvement
  and implemented new features that resulted in a reduction in user complaints and a 15% increase in customer
  satisfaction.

# **Digital Marketing at Perum Perumnas**

August 8th 2022 – November 8th, 2022

- Analyzing users who visit the website, by targeting at least 10-30 visitors per month using Google Analytics tools.
- Increase the number of purchase opportunities by successfully advertising products on social media and optimizing the use of SEO in marketing.
- Managing social media including setting up a posting schedule, for example for national days in the calendar at least 2 to 3 posts, after which it is analyzed to increase brand awareness.

## **Copy Writer, Content Writer at Perum Perumnas**

August 8th 2022 – November 8th, 2022

- Write content for sales needs, such as discounts and the like, at least one day is 1 content ideas design.
- Create concepts to increase brand awareness or sales video scripts and write scripts at least 3 times a week.
- Successfully conceptualize innovative advertising and marketing campaigns for products to be sold.

# ORGANIZATIONAL EXPERIENCE

# **Intern Leader Perum Perumnas**

*August 2022 – October 2022* 

- Serve as a leader for fellow intern candidates in charge of organizing attendance, division of tasks.
- Given the responsibility to select the committee from fellow intern candidates who are suitable for the committee position needed if there is a special event in the company.

# Communication and Information Division, FKDK STMIK Rosma

July 2021 – June 2022

- Responsible for monitoring social media, including interacting in the comment section and creating content on a weekly basis at least 3 content ideas and creating special content for national days.
- Managing and maintaining FKDK STMIK Rosma website which includes updating blogs or news on the web so that the information on the web is always up to date.

## **SKILLS**

**Soft Skill** : Communication, Organizing, Responsibility, Time Management

Hard Skill : Advertising, Copywriter, Content Writer, SEO, Social Media, WordPress

Interest : Analytics, Business Analysis, Campaigns, SEM

Achievements: Google Analytics Certifications Skillshop, Hubspot Academy Digital Marketing Certified